theathletesfoot.com.au 2019-03-05

# Privacy Policy

Privacy policy

The Athlete’s Foot Australia Pty Limited (ABN 57 001 777 582) and its related and associated bodies corporate together with its franchisees trading under The Athlete’s Foot (us, we, our) maintain a policy of strict confidence concerning your (you, your) personal information (Privacy Policy). This Privacy Policy has been developed in accordance with the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) (Privacy Act). This Privacy Policy applies to the collection, storage, use and disclosure by us of your personal information. By accessing this site www.theathletesfoot.com.au (Site) you accept the terms of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy applies to information provided to us whether via this Site or any other means such as in our stores and demonstrates how we will comply with the Australian Privacy Principles under the Privacy Act. 

Although we will comply with this Privacy Policy in respect of information provided to us by persons under the age of 18 years, those persons must obtain the consent of a parent or guardian prior to using the Site and the parent or guardian will be responsible for appropriately supervising the person’s use of the Site.

If you have any further questions or if you wish to receive more information on our information practices and Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Officer at [myfitrewards@taf.com.au](mailto:myfitrewards@taf.com.au)

Collecting personal information

The types of personal information we collect include contact details such as name, email, phone and mailing address. If it is reasonable and practical to do so, we will collect personal information directly from you for you to join our loyalty program. This will include contact details and other information relevant to providing services to you. This may take place in a number of ways, such as via your use of our Site, when you purchase in store or when you become a member of MyFit Rewards.

We may also collect personal information from third parties such as Milestone Sports Ltd and its software application, your representatives or publicly available sources of information. All personal information that we or our related bodies corporate collect, is reasonably necessary for the provision of our goods and services to our customers and for the purposes of marketing communications. 

If someone other than you provide us with personal information about you that we did not ask for, we will notify you as soon as practicable, unless we receive it with your consent. This notice will be given unless to do so would be in breach of an obligation of confidence. If we could not have collected this personal information, we will lawfully de-identify or destroy that personal information.

Contact us forms

When you complete a contact, us form on the Site, you are asked to provide certain information about yourself. This information includes your name, address, email address, phone number and any comments you might have. We use this information to assist your enquiry and learn more about our customers, so we can provide you with the content and feedback information most relevant to you. Once you submit a contact us form on our Site you are no longer anonymous to us.

Sensitive information

Sensitive Information, as defined in the Privacy Act, includes information about a person‘s race or ethnic origin; political opinions or membership of a political association; religious beliefs or affiliations; philosophical beliefs; professional or trade association membership or trade union membership; sexual preference or practices; criminal record or health information.

The Athlete's Foot Australia will not collect or disclose sensitive information about a person unless an exception applies. Exceptions include:

(a) Where that person has given their express consent to do so and the information is reasonably necessary for us to carry out our functions or activities,

An example of express consent includes where a person provides their express consent for us to share their health-related information with a podiatrist through our “MyFit” program.

(b) the use of this information is required or authorised by law or a court or tribunal order,

(c) when the information is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim, or

(d) the collection is necessary to prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to life or health of that person.

We will not collect personal information unless the information is reasonably necessary for or directly related to one, or more of our functions or activities. If we are unable to collect personal information we reasonably require, we may not be able to do business with you or the organisation with which you are connected.

Cookies

Cookies are small text files that are stored on your browser or device by websites, apps, online media, and advertisements. We use cookies and other identification technologies on our Site for a number of purposes, including: to determine the popularity of content, to deliver and measure the effectiveness of advertising campaigns, to analyse site traffic and trends, and to generally understand the online behaviours and interests of people who interact with our services.  Cookies obtained by The Athlete’s Foot are kept for a maximum of 30 days before being deleted.

No data obtained from our use of cookies is shared or given to third parties. Additionally, the data obtained from our use of cookies is not linked to any personal information you may provide and cannot be used to identify you. 

You have the right to choose whether or not to accept cookies, by configuring your computer so that it disables cookies or does not accept them. For further information about cookies, including information setting out how to view the cookies have been set on your device and how to manage and delete them, you can visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

Use and disclosure of information

We may use personal information about you for the primary purpose of providing you with our goods and services, and for other purposes that you would reasonably expect us to use that information such as marketing communications. This includes sending you information about new developments, products, services and offers by post, telephone or electronic communication. You authorise us to use your address or other contact information that you provide to us for this purpose.

We may provide certain information about you including your personal information to our related bodies corporate.

We will not disclose your personal information to any third party other than as set out in this Privacy Policy. In order to deliver our goods and services to you, we may disclose your personal information to other organisations, only in relation to us providing our goods and services to you. We will take reasonable steps to ensure that these organisations are bound by privacy obligations in relation to the protection of your personal information. We may disclose your personal information to other organisations which have a differing privacy policy to ours. For example, when you sign up for the MilestonePod and/or the MyFit App you are agreeing to Milestone Sport Ltd use of your information as set out in their privacy policy which is available at http://www.milestonepod.com/legal/privacy-policy/

Direct marketing

We may use personal information about you for the primary purpose of providing you with our services, and for other purposes for which you would reasonably expect us to use that information. This includes sending you information about new developments, products, services and special offers by post, telephone or any form of electronic communication. You authorise us to use any email address or other contact information you provide to us at any time for this purpose.

You can, at any time, opt out of receiving marketing material by contacting us. You agree and acknowledge that even if you opt out of receiving marketing material, we will still send you essential information that we are legally required to send you relating to the goods and services we provide. Once you opt out of receiving marketing material from us, you agree and acknowledge that this removal from our distribution lists may take several business days after the date of your request for removal.

Accuracy of your information

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information held by us is accurate, up-to-date, complete, relevant and not misleading. If you believe that any of your personal information is not accurate, up-to-date, complete or relevant, or that it may be misleading, please contact us (see below) and we will take all reasonable steps to correct your personal information within a reasonable time.

Third parties and your information

We will only collect, store, use or disclose your personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy unless we are required by law to protect our rights or property (or those of any third party), or to avoid injury to any person.

Although the Site may link directly to websites operated by third parties (Linked Sites), you acknowledge that Linked Sites are not operated by us. We encourage you to always read the applicable privacy policy of any Linked Site on entering the Linked Site. We are not responsible for the content or practices of the Linked Sites nor their privacy policies regarding the collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information.

Disclosure of information overseas

We may transfer your personal information to people in foreign countries to fulfil our business purposes, for example for the purposes of processing. By providing your personal information you consent to this transfer.

Your consent

By your use of the Site you consent to the collection, storage, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and as otherwise permitted under the Privacy Act. 

Storage and security of your personal information

We will use all reasonable endeavours to keep your personal information in a secure environment, however, this security cannot be guaranteed. We have put in place various methods including firewalls, pass worded access and encryption software to ensure your personal information is not subject to misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

If we no longer need your personal information, unless we are required under Australian law or a court or tribunal order to retain it, we will take reasonable steps to destroy or de-identify your personal information in accordance with our document retention policy.

Variation

We may vary the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time. You should check this Privacy Policy regularly so that you are aware of any variations. You will be deemed to have consented to such variations by your continued use of the Site following such changes being made.

Access to information we hold about you

Should you wish to access, update or correct personal information supplied to us, you may email us at [myfitrewards@taf.com.au](mailto:myfitrewards@taf.com.au). There is no cost to request or update your information but we may charge you a reasonable fee to cover our costs in locating and extracting that information to supply it to you. You have the option to either not identify yourself or to use a pseudonym when you contact us, unless it is impractical for us to communicate with you in that manner or if we are required or authorised under Australian law, or a court or tribunal order, to deal with individuals who have identified themselves.
